Inventory of the Konstantin Fotic Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Konstantin Fotic Papers
1927-1972
69030
Hoover Institution Archives
61 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes (27 linear feet)
The papers contain office and personal correspondence, reports, writings, speeches, clippings, and printed matter, documenting the politics of the Royal Yugoslav government in exile during World War II, Yugoslav-American relations, and the post-war Serbian and Yugoslav émigré community organizations. Additionally, documents provide detailed information on Serbian and Yugoslav prisoners of war and their immigration to the Dominican Republic and an extensive volume of speeches and writings reflecting Fotic's views on Tito, New Yugoslavia, and communism. Also available on microfilm (73 reels).
Fotic, Konstantin, 1891-1959.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate forms Available
Also available on microfilm (73 reels).
Related Materials
Milan Gavrilovic papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Bo?idar Puric papers, Hoover Institution Archives
?arko Rista Popovic papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
Konstantin Fotic (1891-1959) was born in ?abac, Serbia. His professional career was in diplomacy, serving the Royal Yugoslav government as minister and ambassador to the United States, 1935-1944. Fotic was the last Yugoslav ambassador to the United States before the coalition of New Yugoslav government was formed in 1944.
As an influential political figure in the Royal Yugoslav government, Fotic's later professional career was devoted to Serbian émigrés' call for freedom and democracy for the Serbian people in Yugoslavia. He was an active member of the Serbian émigré community in the United States and served as the president of the Serbian Central National Committee.
Fotic was a political writer and lecturer, writing numerous articles and books expressing his views on the situation in Yugoslavia during World War II, particularly in regard to post-war communism in Yugoslavia and Tito's regime.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers contain office and personal correspondence, reports, writings, speeches, clippings, and printed matter, documenting the politics of the Royal Yugoslav government in exile during World War II, the state of Yugoslav-American relations, and the Serbian and Yugoslav émigré community.
The majority of Fotic's papers consist of office and personal correspondence collected during his diplomatic career as a Royal Yugoslav secretary and ambassador to the United States. The Office files are comprised of diplomatic correspondence, telegrams, reports, and clippings documenting the politics of the Royal Yugoslav government during World War II, Yugoslav-American relations, and the role of Petar II, King of Yugoslavia. Materials also document the part played by Allied countries in the creation of the new Yugoslavia. Fotic's exchanges of letters with Nikola Tesla, a Yugoslav inventor in the United States, indicating the Royal Yugoslav government support of Tesla's research, are of particular interest.
A considerable number of Fotic's writings and speeches reflect his views on the situation in Yugoslavia during World War II, and post-war communism in Yugoslavia and Tito's regime.
The Serbian Central National Committee (SCNO) file documents Fotic's active role in Serbian émigré organizations, and their call for freedom and democracy for the Serbian people in Yugoslavia. Extensive correspondence within the émigré community and its organizations document issues related to the political and economic situation in Yugoslavia under Tito's government, Serbian contributions to the Allied victory in World War II, and the communist dominated government. Among these are open letters addressed to the U.S. president and the General Assembly of the United Nations. The papers also include a Serbian National Federation file documenting the largest Serbian émigré organization's political views concerning émigré defense committees, Serbian prisoners of war, and refugees.
The Yugoslav displaced persons and prisoners of war file consists of correspondence, detailed reports, lists of prisoners of war, clippings and photographs. Documents reveal the role that SCNO and the international refugee organization played in organizing the immigration of Serbian and Yugoslav prisoners of war to the Dominican Republic.
The Subject file includes documents on the Serbian Orthodox Church's involvement in Serbian émigré organizations, materials describing Dra?a Mihailovic's capture and trial, including the Committee for Fair Trial for Dra?a Mihailovic report, and a petition to President Truman, as well as material on Petar II, King of Yugoslavia, documenting his finances and role in émigré politics.
The Tatjana Fotic materials include correspondence of his wife with friends and the Serbian and Yugoslav émigré community. The material reveals Mrs. Fotic's professional academic work and her active role in organizing the United Yugoslav relief fund, particularly the knitting project to provide Yugoslav prisoners of war and refugees with warm clothing.
The Printed matter documents political developments in Yugoslavia and Europe at the end of World War II and Yugoslav émigrés' views on post-war Yugoslavia.
Diplomats--Yugoslavia.; United States--Foreign relations--Yugoslavia.; World War, 1939-1945--Yugoslavia.; Yugoslavia--Emigration and immigration.; Yugoslavia--Foreign relations--United States.; Yugoslavia--History--Axis occupation, 1941-1945.
- Biographical file, 1934-1972 (Box 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of personal documents, household financial records, and correspondence.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by form
  - Personal documents, 1934, 1938, 1944-1954
    - Family passports, 1934, 1938 (Folder 1: 1)
    - Visa and military permits, 1946, 1948 (Folder 1: 2)
    - House file, 1944, 1949 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Pola Fotic, 1945-1954 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Inheritance tax and expenses, undated (Folder 1: 5)
  - Personal correspondence, 1935-1972
    - General, 1935-1972
      - 1935-1936 (Folder 1: 6-7)
      - 1938-1951 (Folder 1: 8-23)
      - 1952-1956 (Folder 1: 24-25)
      - 1952-1956 (Folder 2: 1-10)
      - 1972 (Folder 2: 11)
      - 1945
        - A-G (Folder 2: 12)
        - A-G (Folder 3: 1)
        - O-Z (Folder 3: 3-5)
      - 1946, A-Z (Folder 3: 6-22)
    - Milan Fotic
      - 1939 (Folder 3: 23)
      - 1945 (Folder 3: 24)
      - 1947-1948 (Folder 3: 25-26)
    - Stanislav Krakov, 1949 (Folder 3: 27)
    - Friedrich Ditrich, 1956-1959 (Folder 3: 28)
    - Undated (Folder 3: 29)
- Diaries, 1940-1948, undated
  Contains diaries arranged in chronological order.
  - 1940 (Folder 4: 1)
  - 1942 (Folder 4: 2)
  - 1943 (Folder 4: 3)
  - 1943, 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 1)
  - 1944 (Folder 5: 2)
  - 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 3)
  - 1948, and undated (Folder 5: 4)
- Speeches and writings, 1944-1958 (Box 6-14)
  Material includes articles, book and commentary drafts, research material and notes, correspondence with enclosures, and clippings. Speeches and broadcast transcripts are also included.
  - Articles and book drafts, 1945-1952
    - "Answering Mr. Lippmann, On Eastern Europe: A Communication," The Washington Post, 1945 (Folder 6: 1)
    - "The Balkan Federation," typescript, 1947 (Folder 6: 2)
    - "Behind the Soviet-Tito Split," The Washington Post, undated (Folder 6: 3)
    - "Confession of a 'War Criminal,'" typescript, 1946 (Folder 6: 4)
    - "Foreword," typescript, undated (Folder 6: 5)
    - "Freedom of the Danube," A Weekly Analysis for the American Citizen, Vol. III, No. 35, 1946 (Folder 6: 6)
    - "The Future of the Small Nation," typescript, undated (Folder 6: 7)
    - "How We Got Stuck with Tito," typescript, circa 1950 (Folder 6: 8)
    - "How Strong Is Tito," typescript, 1950 (Folder 6: 9)
    - "In Defence of Mihailovic," reprint, The Atlantic Monthly, undated (Folder 6: 10)
    - "Is the Success of the Marshall Plan Dependent on Eastern Europe?" typescript, undated (Folder 6: 11)
    - "Life behind the Iron Curtain," holograph, undated (Folder 6: 12)
    - "The Political Situation in Yugoslavia Today," Central National Committee of Yugoslavia, 1945, including typescript (Folder 6: 13)
    - "Preamble," holograph, undated (Folder 6: 14)
    - "Tito and the Cold War," typescript, 1950 (Folder 6: 15)
    - "Tito's Plight- Democracy's Opportunity," Human Events, A Weekly Analysis for the American Citizen, Vol. II, No 45, 1950 (Folder 6: 16)
    - "Tito and the Western Democracies," Journal of Central European Affairs, Vol. 11, No. 4, including typescript, 1952 (Folder 6: 17)
    - "The Totalitarian Regime of Tito-Subasich (Suba?ic) in Yugoslavia," typescript, 1945 (Folder 6: 18)
    - "Yugoslavia," The Encyclopaedia Americana, extract, 1948, 1949 (Folder 6: 19-20)
    - "Yugoslavia 1939-1947," holograph, undated (Folder 6: 21)
    - "What to expect of Yugoslavia," typescript, 1950 (Folder 6: 22)
    - "The War We Lost, Yugoslav's Tragedy and the Failure of the West," book draft
      - Book draft, typescript (Folder 6: 23-26)
      - Book draft, typescript (contd.) (Folder 7: 1-7)
      - Book draft, holograph (Folder 7: 8-12)
      - Book draft, holograph (contd.) (Folder 8: 1-7)
  - Research materials, 1941-1950
    Includes notes, clippings, and photographs
    - "The War We Lost, Yugoslav's Tragedy and the Failure of the West," book material, 1941-1948 (Folder 8: 8-15)
    - "The War We Lost, Yugoslav's Tragedy and the Failure of the West," book material, 1941-1948 (contd.) (Folder 9: 1)
    - Tito material, 1949-1950 (Folder 9: 2-5)
  - Commentary on chronological events, 1948-1958, typescript and holograph
    - 1948-1950 (Folder 9: 6-7)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 9: 8)
    - 1952-1953 (Folder 9: 9-10)
    - 1954 (Folder 9: 11-12)
    - 1954 (contd.) (Folder 10: 1-2)
    - 1955 (Folder 10: 3-4)
    - 1955 (Folder 10: 5-9)
    - 1956 (Folder 10: 10-12)
    - 1957 (Folder 11: 1-2)
    - 1958 (Folder 11: 3-6)
  - Correspondence regarding writings, 1944-1952
    - Mailing list for memorandum "The Political Situation in Yugoslavia Today,", 1945 (Folder 11: 7)
    - Mailing list for memorandum "A Nation's Fight for Survival,", 1945 (Folder 11: 8)
    - "The War We Lost, Yugoslav's Tragedy and the Failure of the West," book, 1948-1950 (Folder 11: 9-15)
      - Letters to editors, 1944-1949, 1951-1952, 1957
        - 1944-1949 (Folder 11: 16)
        - 1944-1949 (contd.) (Folder 12: 1-3)
        - 1950-1952 (Folder 12: 4)
        - 1957 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Libraries and public institutions, 1945 (Folder 12: 6-7)
    - Untitled article, 1944 (Folder 12: 8)
    - Notes
      - 1945, typescript (Folder 12: 9-10)
      - 1948, holograph (Folder 12: 11-12)
  - Speeches, 1940-1950
    - Speech transcripts, 1940-1950
      - 1940-1944 (Folder 12: 13-16)
      - 1940-1944 (contd.) (Folder 13: 1-4)
      - 1946 (Folder 13: 5)
      - 1949-1950 (Folder 13: 6)
      - Undated (Folder 13: 7)
    - Radio broadcast transcripts, 1944-1950
      Includes correspondence
      - 1940-1943 (Folder 13: 8)
      - 1944-1946 (Folder 13: 9)
      - 1950 (Folder 13: 10)
    - Interviews, 1944
      - Fotic, Konstantin, 1950 (Folder 13: 11)
      - Nichols, William, 1949 (Folder 13: 12)
      - Todorovic, Borislav, 1944 (Folder 13: 13)
    - Lectures, 1946-1953
      Includes correspondence, clippings, notes, and photographs
      - 1944 (Folder 13: 14)
      - 1946-1951 (Folder 13: 15-17)
      - 1946-1951 (contd.) (Folder 14: 1-5)
      - 1953 (Folder 14: 6)
- Office files, 1936-1944 (Box 14-28)
  Consists of correspondence, in the form of telegrams, reports, memoranda, received and sent from the office, financial records, notes, and press releases from the Washington D.C. offices. Arranged by form
  - General office correspondence, 1935-1944
    - 1936-1939 (Folder 14: 7-10)
    - 1941-1943 (Folder 14: 11-19)
    - 1941-1943 (contd.) (Folder 15: 1-5)
    - 1944 (Folder 15: 6-9)
  - Personal correspondence, 1935-1944
    Arranged as received in alphabetical or chronological groups
    - A-H, 1935-1944 (Folder 15: 10-12)
    - I-O, 1937-1944 (Folder 15: 10-12)
    - P-Z, 1935-1944 (Folder 16: 1-6)
    - A-G, 1944 (Folder 16: 7-8)
    - H-N, 1944 (Folder 16: 9-10)
    - O-Z, 1944 (Folder 16: 11-13)
    - Miscellany, 1944-1945 (Folder 16: 14-15)
  - Telegrams and reports, 1939-1948 and undated
    - Chronological Telegrams, 1939-1948
      - 1939 (Folder 17: 1)
      - January-February 1941 (Folder 17: 2)
      - March 1941 (Folder 17: 3)
      - April-May 1941 (Folder 17: 4)
      - June-July 1941 (Folder 17: 5)
      - August-November 1941 (Folder 17: 6)
      - December 1941 (Folder 17: 7)
      - January-February 1942 (Folder 17: 8)
      - March 1942 (Folder 17: 9)
      - April 1942 (Folder 18: 1)
      - May 1942 (Folder 18: 2)
      - June 1942 (Folder 18: 3)
      - July-September 1942 (Folder 18: 4)
      - October 1942 (Folder 18: 5-6)
      - November-December 1942 (Folder 18: 7)
      - January-March 1943 (Folder 18: 8)
      - April-June 1943 (Folder 18: 9)
      - July-August 1943 (Folder 18: 10)
      - September 1943 (Folder 18: 11)
      - October 1943 (Folder 19: 1)
      - November 1943 (Folder 19: 2-3)
      - December 1943 (Folder 19: 4-5)
      - January 1944 (Folder 19: 6-7)
      - February 1944 (Folder 19: 8-9)
      - March 1944 (Folder 19: 10)
      - April 1944 (Folder 19: 11-12)
      - May 1944 (Folder 19: 13)
      - June 1944 (Folder 20: 1)
      - July 1944 (Folder 20: 2-3)
      - August 1944 (Folder 20: 4-5)
      - September 1944 (Folder 20: 6)
      - October-December 1944 (Folder 20: 7)
      - January-February 1945 (Folder 20: 8)
      - March-July 1945 (Folder 20: 9)
      - August 1945 (Folder 20: 10)
      - September-November 1945 (Folder 20: 11)
      - December 1945 (Folder 20: 12)
      - Undated (Folder 20: 13-14)
      - Undated (contd.) (Folder 21: 1-2)
      - 1946 (Folder 21: 3)
      - 1947 (Folder 21: 4)
      - 1948 (Folder 21: 5)
    - Encoded telegrams and reports, 1943-1944 and undated
      - September 1943 (Folder 21: 6)
      - October 1943 (Folder 21: 7)
      - November 1943 (Folder 21: 8-12)
      - December 1943 (Folder 21: 13)
      - December 1943 (contd.) (Folder 22: 1-2)
      - February 1944 (Folder 22: 3)
      - Undated (Folder 22: 4)
    - Dossier A/1, 1943-1945 (Folder 22: 5-7)
    - Dossier No. 1, 1943-1944 (Folder 22: 8-10)
    - Dossier B/1, 1943-1944 (Folder 22: 11-13)
    - Telegrams to/from Dra?a Mihailovic, October 1944?April 1945 (Folder 23: 1-2)
    - Telegrams list, 1944 (Folder 22: 3)
    - Reports, 1934-1946
      - Cairo and London, November-December 1943 (Folder 22: 4)
      - Carigrad, Turkey (Constantinople), 1944-1945 (Folder 22: 5-8)
      - Cuba, 1942 (Folder 22: 9)
      - Denich (Denic), Branislav, 1944-1946 (Folder 23: 10-11)
      - Diary, possibly kept by an espionage agent, typescript, February-April 1941 (Folder 22: 12)
      - Diskusija o preuredivanju dr?ave, 1935 (Folder 22: 13)
      - Kne?evic-Todorovic, 1944-1945 (Folder 22: 14)
      - League of Nations, meeting report, 1942 (Folder 22: 15-16)
      - Mihailovic, Dra?a, telegrams and reports, 1941-1944
      - 1941-1944 (Folder 23: 17-20)
        - American aviators rescued by Dra?a Mihailovic, 1944-1945 (Folder 24: 1)
        - "The Cetniks," a survey of Cetnik activity in Yugoslavia, 1941-1944 (Folder 24: 2)
        - For Roettiger, memorandum, 1944 (Folder 24: 3)
        - Propaganda, 1941-1945 (Folder 24: 4)
        - Robert H. McDowell statement, 1944 (Folder 24: 5)
        - U.S. supplies to Dra?a Mihailovic, 1943, 1944 (Folder 24: 6)
      - Odnosi sa Hravatskim organizacijama, 1939-1944 (Folder 24: 7)
      - Organizational chart of the U.S. Government "War Program," 1942 (Folder 24: 8)
      - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia, 1940-1945 (Folder 24: 9-10)
      - Royal Yugoslav mission, Madrid, 1943-1945 (Folder 24: 11-12)
      - Tesla, Nikola, 1934-1942 and undated (Folder 24: 13-15)
      - Trip to California, May-June, 1941 (Folder 24: 16)
      - United States, Department of State, 1941, 1944-1945 (Folder 24: 17)
      - United States' government on Axis attack on Yugoslavia, 1941 (Folder 24: 18)
      - ?ujevic, Mladen, 1943-1945 (Folder 24: 19-21)
  - Speeches, 1941-1944
    - 1941 (Folder 25: 1)
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 25: 2)
    - 1944 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Printed matter, 1940-1944
    - Clippings, 1940-1944 and undated
    - General Dusan Simovich (Simovic) addresses and transcripts, June 1941 (Folder 25: 4)
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 25: 5)
      - 1941 (Folder 25: 6)
      - 1942 (Folder 25: 7)
      - 1943 (Folder 25: 8)
      - 1944 (Folder 25: 9)
      - Undated (Folder 25: 10)
    - News reports, 1941
      - "American Influence on Balkan Moves" (Folder 25: 11)
      - "American Red Cross Aid to Yugoslav Prisoners of War" (Folder 25: 12)
      - "Serbs, Croats, and Slovenians Unite to Defend Country" (Folder 25: 13)
  - Office administration records, 1939-1945 and undated
    - Invitations, 1939-1944 and undated
      - 1939 (Folder 25: 14)
      - 1941-1943 (Folder 25: 15)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 25: 16)
      - 1944 (Folder 25: 17-18)
      - 1941-1944 and undated (Folder 25: 19-20)
    - Thank you letters, 1943-1944 (Folder 25: 21)
    - Office expenses, 1944-1945
      - Balance sheets, 1944 (Folder 26: 1)
      - Office bills, 1944-1945 (Folder 26: 2-3)
    - Mailing lists, 1942 and undated
      - General, undated (Folder 26: 4)
      - Royal Yugoslav offices in the U.S. and Canada, undated (Folder 26: 5)
      - Clergymen of the Serbian Orthodox Diocese for the U.S. and Canada, undated (Folder 26: 6)
      - Serbian, Croatian, and Slovenian newspapers the U.S., undated (Folder 26: 7)
      - Heads of federal department agencies, May 1942 (Folder 26: 8)
      - Yugoslav consulates, undated (Folder 26: 9)
      - Regents of Yugoslavia, undated (Folder 26: 10)
      - Members of the Yugoslav government under Tito, undated (Folder 26: 11)
      - Informative books on Yugoslavia, undated (Folder 26: 12)
  - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia events file, 1941-1942 and undated
    - Code book (code key) for the Royal Correspondence, circa 1941 (Folder 26: 13)
    - Birthday luncheon invitations, 1941 (Folder 26: 14-15)
    - Visit to the United States, June-July 1942
      - Schedule (Folder 26: 16)
      - Luncheon, invitation lists and accepted invitations (Folder 26: 17-22)
      - Luncheon, invitation lists and accepted invitations (contd.) (Folder 27: 1-2)
      - Dinner invitations (Folder 27: 3)
      - Reception, invitation lists, accepted and rejected invitations (Folder 27: 4-10)
      - Meetings with diplomats (Folder 27: 11)
      - Speeches (Folder 27: 12)
      - Stationery (Folder 28: 1)
      - Clippings (Folder 28: 2)
- Serbian Central National Committee (Srpski Centralni Narodni Odbor ? SCNO), 1932-1958 and undated (Box 28-41)
  Contains correspondence, reports, memorandum, open letters, speeches, clippings, and radio broadcasts. Arranged by form
  - Correspondence, 1941-1958 and undated
    arranged in groups, then chronologically
    - General, 1941-1958 and undated
      - Undated (Folder 28: 3-4)
      - 1941-1944 (Folder 28: 5)
      - 1945 (Folder 28: 6)
      - 1946 (Folder 28: 7-9)
      - 1947 (Folder 28: 10-15)
      - 1947 (contd.) (Folder 29: 1-6)
      - 1948 (Folder 29: 7-14)
      - 1948 (contd.) (Folder 30: 1-3)
      - 1949 (Folder 30: 4-16)
      - 1950 (Folder 30: 17-19)
      - 1951 (Folder 30: 20-24)
      - 1951 (contd.) (Folder 31: 1)
      - 1952 (Folder 31: 2-13)
      - 1953 (Folder 31: 14-20)
      - 1954 (Folder 31: 21)
      - 1955 (Folder 31: 22)
      - 1956 (Folder 31: 23)
      - 1957 (Folder 31: 24-25)
      - 1958 (Folder 31: 26-27)
      - Enclosures in letters, 1941-1958 and undated. (Folder 31: 28)
        Includes memoranda, press releases, clippings, and writings
    - By subject, 1944-1954
      - Aid to Tito's regime, 1954 (Folder 32: 1)
      - Jovanovic, Slobodan, 1953-1954 (Folder 32: 2-3)
      - Justice Department, 1945-1946 (Folder 32: 4-6)
      - Metropolitan of Montenegro, Arsenije (Folder 32: 7)
      - State Department, 1944-1951
        - Petition, 1951 (Folder 32: 8)
        - Visa sponsorship, 1944-1947 (Folder 32: 9-10)
      - Suba?ic agreement, 1943-1945. (Folder 32: 11)
      - Subotic, 1945 (Folder 32: 12)
      - Trip to Europe, 1948 (Folder 32: 13-14)
      - Truman, Harry S., 1946 (Folder 32: 15)
      - United Nations conference, San Francisco, 1945 (Folder 32: 16)
      - Visa applications, 1939-1950. (Folder 32: 17)
        Includes
      - White House, the President of the United States, 1944-1945 and undated (Folder 32: 18-19)
      - Yugoslav claims, 1949 (Folder 33: 1)
      - Yugoslav émigrés in Italy, 1944-1945 (Folder 33: 2-3)
      - ?ujovic, Mladen, 1945-1954
        - 1945-1946 (Folder 33: 4)
        - 1947 (Folder 33: 5)
        - 1948 (Folder 33: 6-7)
        - 1949-1951 (Folder 33: 8-14)
        - 1951, 1953 (Box 34: 1)
        - 1954 (Folder 34: 2-3)
        - 1955 (Folder 34: 4)
    - Serbian and Yugoslav émigré communities, 1941-1956
      - Australia, 1946-1947, 1950-1953 (Folder 34: 5)
      - Austria, 1946-1951 (Folder 34: 6-7)
      - Belgium, 1945-1948 (Folder 34: 8)
      - Canada, 1949-1956 (Folder 34: 9-14)
      - Egypt, 1945-1947 (Folder 34: 15)
      - France, 1945-1951. (Folder 34: 16-20)
        Includes 20 photographs from Jovan A. Brkic archive, depicting "Arnautsko-Albansko fasistico vodjstvo", 1941-1947
      - Germany, 1945-1950 (Folder 35: 1-3)
      - Greece, 1946-1951 (Folder 35: 4)
      - Italy, 1945-1951 (Folder 35: 5-9)
      - South America, 1945-1952 (Folder 35: 10-15)
      - Spain, 1946-1947 (Folder 35: 16)
      - Sweden, 1951 (Folder 35: 17)
      - Switzerland, 1944-1945 (Folder 35: 18-21)
      - Switzerland, 1946-1950 (Folder 36: 1-3)
      - Turkey, 1945-1952 (Folder 36: 4)
      - United Kingdom, 1948-1952 (Folder 36: 5)
      - United States (Slovenians in America), 1947-1952 (Folder 36: 6-7)
      - Yemen, 1946 (Folder 36: 8)
    - Serbian and Yugoslav émigré organizations, 1941-1956
      - Centralni Nacionalni Komitet Kraljevine Yugoslavia, 1944-1945 (Folder 36: 9)
      - Narodni Ravnogorski pokret za Ameriku, 1950-1954 (Folder 36: 10)
      - Organizacija Srpskih Cetnika, 1952-1956 (Folder 36: 11)
      - Ravnogorski odbor u Parizu, France, 1947-1950 (Folder 36: 12)
      - Serbian National Defence Council in America
        - 1946-1956 (Folder 36: 13-17)
        - 1946-1956 (contd.) (Folder 37: 1-11)
      - Serbian National Defence Council in Australia, 1953 (Folder 37: 12)
      - Serbian National Defence Council in Canada, 1946, 1952 (Folder 37: 13)
      - Serbian National Defence Council in Germany, 1953-1954 (Folder 37: 14)
      - Srpski Narodni Pokert u Moosburg, Germany, 1945 (Folder 37: 15)
      - Udru?enje Slobodnih gradanja Jugoslavije, London, 1952 (Folder 37: 16)
      - Jugoslavenski Narodni Odbor (Yugoslav National Committee), London, 1945-1948 (Folder 37: 17-19)